Andre Azzolini

Senior Full-Stack Engineer

apazzolini@gmail.com | https://azzolini.io

I'm a full-stack engineer in Dallas, TX that specializes in modern JS development. I view programming as a craft to be appreciated not only for the end product, but also for the code itself. There's a strong tie between the elegance and simplicity of a codebase and its correctness, performance, and ability to handle change.

Experience

MVPindex (Senior / Lead Developer)

March 2016 - Present

- · Designed and programmed a robust framework for ingesting hundreds of millions of social network posts. (Kafka, Node.js)
- · Optimized system performance by introducing a multi-node Elasticsearch cluster and Pilosa with near-real-time syncing.
- Created an internal dashboard to monitor ingestion and jobs status, history, and logs. (React v16, websockets)
- Exposed access to data via a permission-driven API used by the Insights app, the admin app, and customers directly. (Hapi)
- · Architected a jobs framework and implemented several jobs to ensure data quality and perform various ETL tasks. (Node.js)
- Reduced infrastructure expense by 5 figures on AWS by improving app performance and containerizing with Docker.

Freelancer October 2014 — March 2016

- · Created a web application from a Material Design specification for interfacing with Cisco telephony equipment. (Angular)
- Implemented a real-time interface for managing directory touchscreens in commercial buildings. (Angular, Node.js, Firebase)
- Architected a customizable dashboard that integrated internal systems for a health services company. (Angular, Spring)
- Managed a team working on automating flows for a telecommunication company's ordering system. (Scala, Akka)
- Designed an integration testing framework to facilitate CI for a large Dockerized microservices project. (Node.js)

Broadleaf Commerce (Senior Engineer)

October 2011 - October 2014

- Designed and implemented several large, key components of the Broadleaf Commerce codebase. (Spring, Hibernate)
- Oversaw multiple concurrent client implementations and fostered positive, ongoing relationships.

Credera (Consultant) May 2010 — October 2011

- Programmed multiple subsystems of an eCommerce site for a Fortune 1000 company. (Java, Spring, HTML/CSS/JS)
- Performed infrastructure tasks including JVM tuning, handling deploys, and debugging production issues. (httpd, Tomcat)

Skills

- Frontend: ES2018, React, Redux, Immutable.js, Jest, Babel/Webpack, CSS3/SASS, HTML5
- Backend: Node.js, Hapi, Express, Kafka, Aurora/MySQL, GraphQL, Elasticsearch, PostgreSQL, Java, Scala, Akka
- Devops: Unix, OS X, AWS, Docker, Gitlab, CI/CD, deployment configuration, server management, security/cryptography

Personal Projects

- https://pubg.sh: 2D interactive replays of video game matches using React, GraphQL, and canvas
- apazzolini/pgr: A wrapper library around node-postgres providing templated gueries, transactions, and other utils

Education

The University of Texas at Austin

December 2010

Bachelor degrees in Computer Science and Management Information Systems